Guide to the Stanford Alumni Association, Summer Alumni College, Audiorecordings
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Alumni Association, Summer Alumni College, audiorecordings
1966-1973
SC0514
Stanford Alumni Association
1.5 Linear feet
Tapes (reel to reel) from the 1966 session on man and his environment include a complete set of the lectures by Hubert Marshall, political science, Robert McAfee Brown, religious studies, Donald J. Kennedy, biological sciences, and Albert J. Guerard, literature. Tapes from the 1967 session on man's self-knowledge include lectures by Paul R. Ehrlich, biology, and Lewis W. Spitz, history. Tapes from the 1973 session on China include lectures by Michael Sullivan, art, Victor Li, politics and law, Roxanne Witke, culture, and Lyman Van Slyke, history.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 1981, and gift of Mrs. Harold Gast, 1985.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Summer Alumni College of the Stanford Alumni Association was started in 1966. Each summer had a general theme and the faculty was drawn from the Stanford professoriate. The college was open to Stanford alumni, their spouses, and to parents of Stanford students.
Description of the Collection
Tapes (reel to reel) from the 1966 session on man and his environment include a complete set of the lectures by Hubert Marshall, political science, Robert McAfee Brown, religious studies, Donald J. Kennedy, biological sciences, and Albert J. Guerard, literature. Tapes from the 1967 session on man's self-knowledge include lectures by Paul R. Ehrlich, biology, and Lewis W. Spitz, history. Tapes from the 1973 session on China include lectures by Michael Sullivan, art, Victor Li, politics and law, Roxanne Witke, culture, and Lyman Van Slyke, history.
Access Terms
Brown, Robert McAfee, 1920-2001.; Ehrlich, Paul R.; Guérard, Albert J. (Albert Joseph), 1914-; Kennedy, Donald, 1931-; Li, Victor H.; Marshall, Hubert.; Spitz, Lewis William, 1922-; Stanford Alumni Association; Sullivan, Michael, 1916-; Van Slyke, Lyman P.; Witke, Roxanne.; Audiotapes.; Continuing education.
Collection Contents
- Audiorecordings
  - Marshall, Hubert, Lecture I "Pluralism - dividing power to preserve liberty", 1966; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Marshall, Hubert, Lecture II "Equality and the welfare state", 1966; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Marshall, Hubert, Lecture III "Poverty and the urban Negro", 1966; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Marshall, Hubert, Lecture IV "Communism, American foreign policy, and the underdeveloped nations", 1966; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Brown, Robert McAfee, Lecture I "The affirmation of the secular", 1966; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Brown, Robert McAfee, Lecture II "Toward a theology of the secular", 1966; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Brown, Robert McAfee, Lecture III "The Protestant principle--right to dissent", 1966; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Brown, Robert McAfee, Lecture IV "The ongoing reformation", 1966; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Kennedy, Donald J., Lecture I "Contemporary biological problems", 1966; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Kennedy, Donald J., Lecture II "Biological nature of man", 1966; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Kennedy, Donald J., Lecture III "Biology and social issues", 1966; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Kennedy, Donald J., Lecture IV "Science, society and public policy", 1966; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Guerard, Albert J., Lecture I "The American heritage and environment", 1966; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Guerard, Albert J., Lecture II "Personal visions of solitude and alienation", 1966; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Guerard, Albert J., Lecture III "Personal visions of solitude and alienation (cont.)", 1966; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Guerard, Albert J., Lecture IV "The grotesque and the comic in the contemporary novel", 1966; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Ehrlich, Paul R., Lecture I, 1967; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 3)
  - Ehrlich, Paul R., Lecture II, 1967; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 3)
  - Ehrlich, Paul R., Lecture III, 1967; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 3)
  - Ehrlich, Paul R., Lecture IV, 1967; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 3)
  - Spitz, Lewis W., Lecture I, 1967; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 3)
  - Spitz, Lewis W., Lecture II, 1967; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 3)
  - Spitz, Lewis W., Lecture III, 1967; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 3)
  - Spitz, Lewis W., Lecture IV, 1967; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 3)
  - Sullivan, Michael, Lectures 13 and 14, 1973; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 3)
  - Van Slyke, Lyman, Lectures 1 and 2, 1973; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 3)
  - Li, Victor, Lectures 7 and 8, 1973; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 3)
  - Li, Victor, Lectures 15 and 16, 1973; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 3)
  - Witke, Roxanne, Lectures 9 and 10, 1973; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 3)
  - Summer Alumni College, Tresidder Memorial Union, 1973 Aug 25; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 3)
  - Lewis, 1973 Aug 24; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 3)